martindale.com 2012-09-20

# Privacy Policy - martindale.com

(Last updated April 16, 2012)

To underscore our commitment to privacy and our vision that good privacy is good business, we have adopted this online privacy policy for martindale.com®, Lawyers.comSM, Attorneys.comSM, LawyerLocatorSM, and Martindale-Hubbell® Client Service Center (collectively; "our website") and their mobile equivalents including mobile applications (collectively, "mobile application"), which are commonly owned or operated by LexisNexis, a division of Reed Elsevier Inc. and its affiliated companies ("LexisNexis"). You may also have been directed to this Online Privacy Policy from other websites owned or operated by LexisNexis that have adopted this Online Privacy Policy.

This Online Privacy Policy only applies to information collected through our website and the mobile application. You may have also been directed to this Online Privacy Policy from other websites owned or operated by LexisNexis and/or its affiliates that have adopted this policy. Our website and mobile application are not directed at children under the age of 13.

 **Information Collection**

 **I. Personally Identifiable Information**

Personally identifiable information collected from our website and our mobile application may include, for example, your name, photograph, email address, demographic information, telephone number(s), facsimile numbers, social and professional networks, employer, job title, bar association details, your professional experience and credentials, your education, your hobbies and interests and information relating to any orders you place, or any inquiries you may make through our website or our mobile application

In addition, our mobile application, with your consent, also may collect information about your current location. Our mobile application may also collect your device's unique identifier and other technical information.

 **II. Cookies**

"Cookies" are small pieces of information that are stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. Our website uses first-party and third-party cookies, however personally identifiable information is not collected through the use of cookies. Cookies are used to track user IDs and passwords, provide tailored content, and determine whether a visitor is unique or whether the visitor has viewed our website before.

While most browsers are set to accept cookies by default, you can set yours to refuse cookies or to alert you before accepting them. Your browser manufacturer has information on changing the default setting for your specific browser. Deleting or refusing to accept cookies from our website, however, may limit your ability to use some portions of our site which require the use of cookies to operate effectively.

 **III. Non-personally identifiable information**

Our website and our mobile application also collect non-personally identifiable information. For example, as you browse our website or use our mobile application we may collect information about your visit, but not about you personally. Via web server logs, for example, we may monitor statistics such as: the number of people that visit our website, which page(s) are visited on our website, from which domain our visitors come (e.g., aol.com, hotmail.com, etc.), and which browsers people use to visit our website (e.g., Microsoft Internet Explorer, Safari, Mozilla Firefox, etc.). We also may compile statistics that show the numbers and frequency of visitors to our website or the mobile application. These aggregated statistics may be used internally to improve our website or the mobile application and for product development and marketing purposes generally. The aggregated statistics may also be provided to advertisers and other third parties, but again, the statistics contain no personally identifiable information. We may use an outsourcing program to assist us in analyzing this data to better tailor our website.

The mobile application may collect non-personally identifiable information such as the type of device you are using (Apple® iPhone®, iPad®, or Android™ phone) and the version of mobile operating system that your device is using.

 **Information Use and Consumer Choice**

The information collected by our website and our mobile application is used for responding to your inquiries and otherwise corresponding with you, for processing transactions you request, maintaining your account (if you have one), for customer support functions; for other purposes permitted by your organization's subscriber agreement(s) (if any) for products and services, to maintain the security and integrity of our websites, applications, products and services; for the purpose of conducting market research or surveys on behalf of LexisNexis; for research, statistical or historical purposes; and for the administration, review and/or the improvement of the content of our websites, applications, products and services. For example, we use information provided to us to customize your experiences on our website in various ways, such as suggesting news articles or member posts that may be of interest or displaying recent status updates from your connections when you log in to martindale.com Connected. Similarly, your information may be used to enhance the experience of your connections.

We may use information about searches or submissions that users provide to us as part of our customer care functions to contact you in response to your comments or inquiries, as part of the maintenance of your account with us (if you have one), or in order to complete a transaction that you requested. In addition, we may also use this type of information to enhance our products and services or to communicate to you about products and services that may be of interest to you, but we will offer you the opportunity not to receive such communications. Similarly, if you sign up to receive newsletters or to be added to one of our mailing lists, you will be able to "unsubscribe" from these communications at any time.

You also have choices about the sharing of information that you include in your martindale.com® Connected profile with other users, if applicable. More information about these choices is described in the My Connected Settings section below.

Our website or our mobile application may use third-party advertising companies and advertising networks to serve ads and collect information when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, phone number or email address) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements on this and other websites about goods and services that may be of interest to you.

If you choose to use our service to tell someone about our website or our mobile application or a particular product or service, we will ask you for that person's name and e-mail address. We will automatically send that person a one-time e-mail message with information about the product or service and/or inviting him or her to visit our website or use our mobile application. This message may include your name and/or e-mail address and any optional message that you elect to send along with our e-mail. We do not retain the information that you provide as part of this service (although we may retain the e-mail address of the person you suggest if he or she requests to receive additional information or e-mail messages from us). 

**Onward Transfer**

We may disclose information you provide to us to third parties in order to complete a transaction that you requested or as otherwise permitted by your user agreement(s) (if any).

We may share information you provide to us through our website or our mobile application with third party applications that use information from our website for the benefit of their end users. For example, a third party application may want to display your martindale.com profile information to you or other users through their application. Our contracts with these third party application developers do not permit them to retain, share, or store any personally identifiable information except to provide these services, and they are bound by confidentiality agreements limiting the use of your information. We will only share personally identifiable information that you provide about yourself with these third party application developers with your consent or, in the case of information that you make available to another martindale.com Connected user, if that member consents to the use of a third party application that requires information about you that you have shared in order to work.

If you choose to make information available to other people through instant messages, status updates, group forum discussions, electronic mail messages, blog postings, your profile (if any), registering for an event, or by joining groups or using other networking functions that we may offer on our website, this information will be visible to these third parties. Please take care in deciding what information you choose to make available through these mechanisms, as we do not control the manner in which recipients or persons who may see the information may use or re-disclose the information that you choose to provide.

We also may disclose information you provide to us to third parties as permitted by your organization's subscriber agreement(s) (if any). In other cases, it may be necessary to disclose information you provide about yourself or third parties in order to make a disclosure or complete a transaction that you requested.

We may outsource some tasks, including the operation of some website or mobile application functions that require access to information you supply online. In such cases, however, we require that the companies acting on our behalf to institute safeguards to protect the confidentiality of your information.

If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will assume responsibility for the personal information collected by us through our website and our mobile application and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding the information collected through this website or the mobile application, as described in this Online Privacy Policy.

Finally, please note that we may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary in order to comply with the law or legal process. 

**_Martindale.com_ Connected Settings**

Through the account settings section of "martindale.com Connected" area of our website, you can control what information in your profile can be viewed by other martindale.com Connected users or third party applications. For example, if your account setting for certain information is set to be visible to "all martindale.com Connected members," any member of the martindale.com Connected community can access that information and a third party application can retrieve this information only on behalf of that user. You may revoke permission granted to any third party at any time or make other changes to your privacy preferences through the account settings section of "My Connected" area of our website.

This section does not apply to any other area of our website or the mobile application

 **Access and Correction**

As an information company, we know the importance of accurate data. Therefore, we strive to maintain the accuracy of the information collected through our website and our mobile application. Furthermore, we believe that the individual is invaluable in ensuring that data is complete and accurate. We will provide you with access to personally identifiable information you provide through our website or our mobile application for as long as we maintain that information in a readily accessible format. Similarly, we permit and encourage you to correct inaccuracies in the information you submit to us through our website or our mobile application. If you wish to correct any inaccurate information you have submitted to our website or our mobile application, please either use mechanisms provided by our website or the mobile application or send an e-mail to: [Privacy.Information.Mgr@lexisnexis.com.](mailto:mailto:Privacy.Information.Mgr@lexisnexis.com)

The access and correction provisions of this Online Privacy Policy only apply to personally identifiable information collected from you through our website and our mobile application. Individuals that are interested in information about how to access and/or request the correction of personal information LexisNexis maintains about them (such as public record information, insurance claims information, or information for employment background screening) for potential inclusion in information products and services can visit [personalreports.lexisnexis.com](https://personalreports.lexisnexis.com/) or [www.lexisnexis.com/privacy.](http://www.lexisnexis.com/privacy)

 **Security**

We have put in place administrative, technical and physical safeguards designed to protect the information that we collect from you through our website and our mobile application. In the event we request or transmit sensitive information, such as credit card information or Social Security Numbers, our processes are designed to use industry standard, secure socket layer ("SSL") encryption. We also limit access to personally identifiable information to those employees who need access in order to carry out their job responsibilities. 

We need your help to keep your information secure. Remember to be vigilant in the protection of your computer or mobile device and use common sense security practices, such as safeguarding access to your computer or mobile device, protecting your user IDs and passwords, and installing anti-virus software in accordance with the recommendations of the provider of your computer or mobile device. 

If you are an attorney, you are solely responsible for compliance with applicable rules of professional responsibility and ethical obligations to clients and prospective clients in your treatment of and responses to their respective inquiries via our website or the mobile application. 

**Other Websites**

This Online Privacy Policy only applies to our website and our mobile application identified in the first paragraph of this privacy policy. Our website and our mobile application, however, may include links to other websites which may be operated by other LexisNexis companies or by third parties. If you visit a website not listed above, we recommend that you review the online privacy policy of that website to determine how the operator of that website will handle personal information collected through that website.

 **Policy Changes**

We may revise this Online Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make any material changes to this Online Privacy Policy, the date of the most recent revision will be indicated above so that you can determine whether there have been any material revisions since your last visit.

If you have questions or concerns regarding this Online Privacy Policy, please contact us at:

LexisNexis  
Privacy, Security and Compliance Organization  
PO Box 933  
Dayton, Ohio 45401  
Telephone: 1-800-526-4902  
Email: [Privacy.Information.Mgr@lexisnexis.com](mailto:Privacy.Information.Mgr@lexisnexis.com)
